KASHFEE HABIB

@ kashfee.habib@gmail.com



London E163HX

Result driven professional with highly developed customer service skills and administrative experience in higher education with 10 plus years of loyal service. Facilitated University programs related to registration, enrolment, convocation, and general student support. Excellent computer, organizational and time management skills with the ability to work on concurrent projects.

EXPERIENCE

04/2015 - 07/2023

Senior Officer, Independent University, Bangladesh, Dhaka

- Processed Graduate and Undergraduate Registration;
- Effectively and clearly deal with a variety of correspondence arising from the registration process;
- worked closely with Finance and Account department on various issues chief among them ironing out discrepancies in relation to payments during registration and course modifications (as done by students);
- Entered student details on the student management system;
- Filled physical and digital copies of important documents/student applications/office memos to maintain consistent and accurate records;
- Actively participated in meeting such Academic Council, and various other committees to record meeting minutes to maintain proper documentation;
- Booked conference rooms, scheduled catering and sent necessary invitations to assist in coordinating events;
- Responsible for management, organization and effective delivery of the Graduation ceremony attended by 1000+ students;
- Created graduation lists, top scoring students lists for graduate and undergraduate students, marshalling during the graduation ceremony, organizing graduation receptions and liaised with 'special award' students before a graduation ceremony to ensure any special requirements are in place before the day of graduation. Provided general administrative support during the entirety of the event;
- Proactively engaged in planning and recommending policy changes for the betterment of the students;
- Carried out the screening process including examination for potential candidates to facilitate smooth recruitment;
- Supervised the issuance of ID cards to all students, faculty members, employees and others as needed;
- Raised appropriate purchase requisitions as needed by the Office.

08/2009 - 03/2015

Registration Officer, Independent University, Bangladesh, Dhaka

- Prepared and issued transcripts, student statuses and any other document as requested by students;
- Oversaw registration processes for incoming students each semester and managed paperwork to facilitate timely services;
- Assisted the Registrar and Deputy Registrar with enrolment counts, faculty load studies, student ranking lists including special studies and statistical analysis;
- Assisted the Registrar and Deputy Registrar in organizing the Convocation;
- Assisted the IT section to provide updates of necessary software to each work station;

- Prepared business cases and costing worksheets for new initiatives for year's budget for the Office of the Registrar;
- Issued Id cards to all students, faculty members, employees and others.

06/2008 - 08/2008

Intern, United News of Bangladesh, Dhaka

- Penned breaking news stories and provided real time updates online;
- Updated the news database periodically;
- Translated news from Bangla to English.

KEY SKILLS

- A fast learner with a proven track record of achievement;
- Proficient in the use of all Microsoft applications;
- Strong collaborator who always puts the needs of the team first;
- Exceptional communication skills;
- An adaptable approach to change.

EDUCATION

2023-2024	16-week skills boot camp in Front End Development is an intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Node.js, and React. edX Boot Camps, UK
2021	Executive Master of Business Administration, Finance Independent University, Bangladesh, Dhaka
2013	Master of Social Science, Development Studies Independent University, Bangladesh, Dhaka
2010	Bachelor of Science, Computer Science Independent University, Bangladesh, Dhaka
2010	Bachelor of Social Science, Media and Communication Independent University, Bangladesh, Dhaka

LANGUAGES

Bengali: First Language	
English:	C2
Proficient	